<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<person xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" ana="historical" xml:id="BIO17984">
    <idno type="TTS">12266</idno>
    <persName type="main">
        <persName xml:lang="zh-Hant">
            <surname>郭</surname>
            <forename>感</forename>
        </persName>
        <persName xml:lang="zh-Latn-alalc97">
            <surname>Guo</surname>
            <forename>Gan</forename>
        </persName>
    </persName>
    <sex value="1">m</sex>
    <floruit>
        <date when="1106" datingMethod="#chinTrad" period="#D15">宋</date>
    </floruit>
    <note>Guo(1) Gan [17984] According to Ye(1) Shi's funerary inscription for his great grandson, Liangchen [17987] (q.v.): "from Gan through his grandson, Zhichang [17986], were [members of a] wealthy [lineage] in the community [lizhong], and in the generation of Liangchen, both he and his brother were literati (shiren); although they were not able to advance through office, despite property division (zifen), decline [of the lineage] was preventable and, for this reason, from the generation of Liangchen, the Guo(1) family day by day greatly advanced." In Ye(1) Shi's funerary inscription for Liangchen's brother, Liangxian [17988] (q.v.):, he says: The fame of the surname Guo(1) has been famous in Dongyang for a long time indeed! From river Zhe and East, amoung numerous great families (dajia), the Guo(1) are placed in front. The Guo(1) do not yet have noble titles and government office, their financial resources (cai) do not exceed those of other people, and yet they can be called a great family (dajia); why? The old customs of Dongyang were that power (qili) was the index to greatness (xiong) . . . The Guo beautify (mei) their family (jia) through the use of classical studies (ruxue) and also know that what the world honors is superiority in scholarship. . .; therefore their sons and younger brothers are not only sought as community and prefectural teachers (xiang zhou xiansheng), but they marry their daughters to famous men (mingren) of the time. . . " On this basis, I am assuming that hereditary status was wealth and the members of the generations previous to Liangchen, Liangxian and their cousin Qinzhi [17989], were engaged in accumulating this wealth.</note>
    <affiliation>
        <note>
            <listPerson>
                <personGrp role="kin"/>
                <listRelation type="kinship">
                    <relation active="#BIO17984" passive="#BIO17985" key="180" sortKey="5" name="S">
                        <desc type="kin-tie">
                            <desc xml:lang="zh-Hant">子</desc>
                            <desc xml:lang="en">S Son</desc>
                            <trait type="mourning" subtype="H">
                                <label xml:lang="zh-Hant">期年(長子眾子同)</label>
                                <desc xml:lang="zh-Hant">夫族</desc>
                                <desc xml:lang="en">Patrilateral Kin of Husband</desc>
                            </trait>
                        </desc>
                    </relation>
                </listRelation>
            </listPerson>
        </note>
    </affiliation>
    <socecStatus>
        <state type="status">
            <desc xml:lang="zh-Hant">富豪</desc>
            <desc xml:lang="en">wealth</desc>
        </state>
    </socecStatus>
    <residence ref="#PL12786" key="1">
        <state>
            <desc xml:lang="zh-Hant">籍貫(基本地址)</desc>
            <desc xml:lang="en">Basic Affiliation</desc>
        </state>
    </residence>
    <note type="created" target="#TTS">
        <date when="2007-03-12"/>
    </note>
</person>