<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<person xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" ana="historical" xml:id="BIO14023">
    <idno type="TTS">8311</idno>
    <persName type="main">
        <persName xml:lang="zh-Hant">
            <surname>章</surname>
            <forename>及</forename>
            <addName type="choronym">豫章</addName>
        </persName>
        <persName xml:lang="zh-Latn-alalc97">
            <surname>Zhang</surname>
            <forename>Ji(3)</forename>
            <addName type="choronym">Yuzhang</addName>
        </persName>
    </persName>
    <sex value="1">m</sex>
    <floruit>
        <date when="0817" datingMethod="#chinTrad" period="#D6">唐</date>
    </floruit>
    <note>Zhang(2) Ji(3) [14023] See documentation for 8th generation descendant, Fu [336]. In tracing the migration and dispersion into Zhejiang of the Yuzhang Zhang(2) during Song, the first Zhejiang Zhang(2) is a Zhang(2) Fu(3) [14049] from Yongkang, jinshi in 1070 and probable descendant of the Zhang(2), who moved from Jianan-s during the Five Dynasties to Hangzhou, Yanguan county and then, at beginning of Song, to Yongkang. The next Zhejiang Zhang(2) is a Cui, jinshi in 1073 from Jiaxing, probably representing a move from Hangzhou, Yanguan (must check--not included until documentary link found with the Jianning Zhang(2)); in addition, by late Southern Song, Zhejiang Zhang(2), not included because of absence of documented linkage, are found in Hangzhou, Yuqian count, Changhua county, Taizhou, Linhai county and Mingzhou, Yinxian county and are all probably descended from one or another branch of the Jianning Zhang(2)). A quick check of Wang Deyi finds Zhang(2) in Guian, Changhua, Suzhou, Chuzhou, and Wuzhou. There are no Jianning Zhang(2) in the Yuan index. The next Song Zhejiang Zhang(2) is Jie [334], a Huzhou, Changxing jinshi in 1124, a grandson of Dun [333], and preceded by his father or uncle Yuan [12969], who moved here from Suzhou (migration target of at least three branches of the Jianning Zhang--Dun's, Jie(3)'s [345] and Fu(2)'s [7012]). Yuan was a son of Dun. Another Jianning (Pucheng) Zhang(2), Yi's [339] son Ju [14047], is the first Chuzhou, Lishui county Zhang(2) in 1148. Also in 1148, there is a Hangzhou jinshi Zhang(2) Chaozong [Zhejiang TZ, 125.12a] and a Lishui jinshi Zhang(2) Mi [22953] [Zhejiang TZ, 125.13b]. Mi is probably distantly related, although there are no shared generational names, and I am treating Mi's family as lineal descendants of Ji(3), who may have moved here before Yi, and as jia k. The next Zhejiang Zhang(2) jinshi are Mu [14050] and Xia(2) [14051], both with water radical in their mingzi and both treated as nephews of Jie [334]. I am including all other Changxing Zhang(2) in the jinshi list as lineage kin of Yi, Jie, et al. and including all other Lishui Zhang(2) as lineage kin of Yi [339] and Ju [14047].</note>
    <affiliation>
        <note>
            <listPerson>
                <personGrp role="kin"/>
                <listRelation type="kinship">
                    <relation active="#BIO14023" passive="#BIO3181" key="255" sortKey="9" name="SSS">
                        <desc>
                            <desc xml:lang="en">SSS</desc>
                            <desc xml:lang="zh-Hant">曾孫; 重孫</desc>
                        </desc>
                    </relation>
                    <relation active="#BIO14023" passive="#BIO14024" key="255" sortKey="9" name="SSS">
                        <desc>
                            <desc xml:lang="en">SSS</desc>
                            <desc xml:lang="zh-Hant">曾孫; 重孫</desc>
                        </desc>
                    </relation>
                    <relation active="#BIO14023" passive="#BIO22950" key="303" sortKey="50" name="G+n">
                        <desc>
                            <desc xml:lang="en">G+n, lineal descendant, generation undefined</desc>
                            <desc xml:lang="zh-Hant">直系後裔</desc>
                        </desc>
                    </relation>
                </listRelation>
            </listPerson>
        </note>
    </affiliation>
    <socecStatus>
        <state type="status">
            <desc xml:lang="en">civil office</desc>
            <desc xml:lang="zh-Hant">[為官者：文]</desc>
        </state>
    </socecStatus>
    <residence ref="#PL15892" key="3">
        <state>
            <desc xml:lang="zh-Hant">前住地</desc>
            <desc xml:lang="en">Former Address</desc>
        </state>
    </residence>
    <residence ref="#PL16033" key="1">
        <state>
            <desc xml:lang="zh-Hant">籍貫(基本地址)</desc>
            <desc xml:lang="en">Basic Affiliation</desc>
        </state>
    </residence>
    <residence ref="#PL16033" key="2">
        <state>
            <desc xml:lang="zh-Hant">遷住地</desc>
            <desc xml:lang="en">Moved to</desc>
        </state>
    </residence>
    <note type="created" target="#TTS">
        <date when="2007-03-12"/>
    </note>
</person>