<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<person xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" ana="historical" xml:id="BIO4113">
    <idno type="TTS">3205</idno>
    <persName type="main">
        <persName xml:lang="zh-Hant">
            <surname>閻</surname>
            <forename>寶</forename>
        </persName>
        <persName xml:lang="zh-Latn-alalc97">
            <surname>Yan</surname>
            <forename>Bao</forename>
        </persName>
    </persName>
    <sex value="1">m</sex>
    <floruit>
        <date when="0935" datingMethod="#chinTrad" period="#D7">五代</date>
    </floruit>
    <note>Yan(4) Bao [4113] Bao was a general who assisted Later Tang emperor, Zhangzong [r. 923-5], take Changshan  and was rewarded by being made Taiyuan Wang. He subsequently moved to Jizhou, Juye county (ancestral address identified in biographical materials for descendant, Xun) and all Juye Yan(4) were his descendants according to all funerary inscriptions. (see Li Zhaoqi, WJ, 30.10a in funerary inscription for 6th generation descendant, Yan(4) C [22743]). According to Chao Buzhi, 68.10a, when Tang fell to Later Jin in 935, Bao was made a zaixiang, but the Five dynasty tables in ERWSBB do not record his name. Li Zhaoqi's funerary inscription for Yan(4) C identifies, by title, an unnamed great grandfather as Yan(4) Yiqing [22738], and Li Zhaoqi's funerary inscription for Yan(4) B [22745] identifies his unnamed great grandfather as the person whose funerary inscription was drafted by Ouyang Xiu, i.e., Yan(4) Xiang [22737], and B's grandfather holds the same title as Yan(4) Yiqing, thereby establishing Xiang as the father of Yiqing. C's father and grandfather both have the same titles as Gai's [22742] father and grandfather and C's nephew was Gai's son, thereby establishing C as a son of Zhongxuan [22741] and a brother of Gai. The remaining problems are 1) where does Deji [4116], father-in-law of Chao(2) Duanben [3024], fit into the genealogy and 2) by what method of count was Bao C's 6th generation ancestor, i.e. was he Xiang's grandfather or great grandfather? I am identifying Deji as a documented (all Juye Yan descend from Bao) nephew of Yiqing, but he may be a son. Xiang earned the jinshi during the Jianlong period (960-62) and Bao was still active in 935 at the earliest. The identification of Bao as a grandfather, rather than great grandfather, of Xiang makes better chronological sense, although either is possible.</note>
    <affiliation>
        <note>
            <listPerson>
                <personGrp role="kin"/>
                <listRelation type="kinship">
                    <relation active="#BIO4113" passive="#BIO22737" key="243" sortKey="8" name="SS">
                        <desc>
                            <desc xml:lang="en">SS Son's son</desc>
                            <desc xml:lang="zh-Hant">孫</desc>
                        </desc>
                    </relation>
                </listRelation>
            </listPerson>
        </note>
    </affiliation>
    <socecStatus>
        <state type="status">
            <desc xml:lang="en">military</desc>
            <desc xml:lang="zh-Hant">[武官]</desc>
        </state>
    </socecStatus>
    <listEvent>
        <event type="09" subtype="77" sortKey="1">
            <head>entry</head>
            <label xml:lang="en">military merit: military service or distinction in battle</label>
            <label xml:lang="zh-Hant">軍員轉補</label>
            <desc type="0" subtype="10">
                <desc xml:lang="en">Military Merit</desc>
                <desc xml:lang="zh-Hant">軍功補授門</desc>
            </desc>
        </event>
    </listEvent>
    <residence ref="#PL14538" key="3">
        <state>
            <desc xml:lang="zh-Hant">前住地</desc>
            <desc xml:lang="en">Former Address</desc>
        </state>
    </residence>
    <residence ref="#PL14888" key="1">
        <state>
            <desc xml:lang="zh-Hant">籍貫(基本地址)</desc>
            <desc xml:lang="en">Basic Affiliation</desc>
        </state>
    </residence>
    <residence ref="#PL14888" key="2">
        <state>
            <desc xml:lang="zh-Hant">遷住地</desc>
            <desc xml:lang="en">Moved to</desc>
        </state>
    </residence>
    <note type="created" target="#TTS">
        <date when="2007-03-12"/>
    </note>
</person>