<person xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" ana="historical" xml:id="BIO17391">
    <idno type="TTS">11675</idno>
    <persName type="main">
        <persName xml:lang="zh-Hant">
            <surname>鮑</surname>
            <forename>君福</forename>
        </persName>
        <persName xml:lang="zh-Latn-alalc97">
            <surname>Bao</surname>
            <forename>Junfu</forename>
        </persName>
    </persName>
    <persName type="alias" key="AKA4">
        <addName>慶臣</addName>
        <term>字</term>
        <addName xml:lang="zh-Latn-alalc97">Qingchen</addName>
        <term>Courtesy name</term>
    </persName>
    <sex value="1">m</sex>
    <floruit>
        <date when="0930" datingMethod="#chinTrad" period="#D11">吳越</date>
    </floruit>
    <note>Bao(2) Junfu [17391] According to Ye(1) Shi's [10749] funerary inscription for Bao(2) Su [17398], his ancestors descended from Bao(2) Shu[ya] [17389], a friend of Guan(2) Zhong [17364], who served as an official under duke Huan of Qi. After four moves, his ancestors settled in Luoyang and at end of Tang, they first moved to Shaoxing and later to Hangzhou where they served in the administration of the WuYue kings. Ancestors Hao [17392] and Shouzhong [17393] held office in Wenzhou and a branch of the lineage (jia) settled there. According to Zheng(1) Xie's [13378] funerary inscription for Bao(2) Zongshi [17417], his ancestors also descended from Bao Shu[ya], whose residence was in the area of Taishan. No mention is made of the immediate previous address. Descendants moved to Shaoxing and his 5th generation ancestor, Junfu, and son, Xiurang [17400] moved to Hangzhou to serve in the administration of the WuYue kings. Junfu's great grandson, Renshuang [17402] accompanied Qian(1) Chu [3037] when he returned to allegiance to Song and moved to Kaifeng where this branch of the lineage declined (yishuai). Another great grandson, Dang [17403], remained in Hangzhou and this branch of the lineage prospered. In Zhen(1) Dexiu's [10258] funerary inscription for Bao(2) Cuiran [17415], he traces ancestry through a move from Kaifeng to Shaoxing and then to Chuzhou, Longquan county. Zhen Dexiu does not mention Shuya. Since Longquan county resident, Biao [17406], was a lineage uncle of Yongjia resident Xiao, according to Ye(1) Shi, the Longquan and Yongjia Bao(2) clearly have a common ancestor. I am going to treat the Hangzhou, Wenzhou, and Chuzhou Bao as branches of a common lineage that traces its ancestry back to Bao(2) Can [17390] and then to Shuya. Jia 'a,' as direct and documented descendants of Junfu, who remained in Hangzhou, jia 'b,' as beginning with the grandson of Junfu (not named), Hao [17392], who moved to Yongjia, and jia 'c,' beginning with the first Longquan Bao jinshi, Dayi [17404], who will be treated as a 6th generation descendant of Bao Can (and lineage cousin of Ke [17394]) as will Dabai [23367], great grandfather of Shenlv [17485]. I will only include those jinshi descendants of Dayi, whose generational names parallel those of Cuiran's patrilineal ancestors, An+x, etc. (making the An+x generation nephews of Dayi) and those of Biao (hypothesizing that Shenyou [1414], was a great grandnephew of Dayi and that Biao was a nephew of Shenyou). See documentation for Bao(2) Zongshi, Bao(2) Su, and Bao(2) Cuiran. These earlier hypotheses were proven correct through the 1148 jinshi listings for Shenlv and Qiao. I am making Dayi and Dabai brothers. Dabai's great grandson, Yaoqing [23368] (who founded his branch of the family (weihu in 1148 jinshi listing for younger brother, Shenlv) earned the jinshi in 1097, whereas his brother, Shenlv earned it in 1148 at age 27. Another brother, Qian's son, Cuiran, earned wth jinshi in 1181. The long spread of years between birth of brothers is not uncommon, but it indicates that Dayi was active at the earliest in 1037 and latest in 1101, which would make a good guess of his actual active year being in the 1060s. I am making all the Bao An+x, not otherwise identified, as nephews of both Dayi and Dabai.[Kinship with Hao is not yet checked. 與鮑皓的親戚關係未考。]</note>
    <affiliation>
        <note>
            <listPerson>
                <personGrp role="kin"/>
                <listRelation type="kinship">
                    <relation active="#BIO17391" passive="#BIO17390" key="75" sortKey="-1" name="F">
                        <desc type="kin-tie">
                            <desc xml:lang="zh-Hant">父</desc>
                            <desc xml:lang="en">F Father</desc>
                            <trait type="mourning" subtype="AG">
                                <label xml:lang="zh-Hant">斬衰三年</label>
                                <desc xml:lang="zh-Hant">本宗血親</desc>
                                <desc xml:lang="en">Agnates</desc>
                            </trait>
                        </desc>
                    </relation>
                    <relation active="#BIO17391" passive="#BIO17392" key="243" sortKey="8" name="SS">
                        <desc type="kin-tie">
                            <desc xml:lang="zh-Hant">孫</desc>
                            <desc xml:lang="en">SS Son's son</desc>
                            <trait type="mourning" subtype="H">
                                <label xml:lang="zh-Hant">大功</label>
                                <desc xml:lang="zh-Hant">夫族</desc>
                                <desc xml:lang="en">Patrilateral Kin of Husband</desc>
                            </trait>
                        </desc>
                    </relation>
                    <relation active="#BIO17391" passive="#BIO17400" key="180" sortKey="5" name="S">
                        <desc type="kin-tie">
                            <desc xml:lang="zh-Hant">子</desc>
                            <desc xml:lang="en">S Son</desc>
                            <trait type="mourning" subtype="H">
                                <label xml:lang="zh-Hant">期年(長子眾子同)</label>
                                <desc xml:lang="zh-Hant">夫族</desc>
                                <desc xml:lang="en">Patrilateral Kin of Husband</desc>
                            </trait>
                        </desc>
                    </relation>
                </listRelation>
            </listPerson>
        </note>
    </affiliation>
    <socecStatus>
        <state type="status">
            <desc xml:lang="zh-Hant">[為官者：文]</desc>
            <desc xml:lang="en">civil office</desc>
        </state>
    </socecStatus>
    <residence ref="#PL15767" key="1">
        <state>
            <desc xml:lang="zh-Hant">籍貫(基本地址)</desc>
            <desc xml:lang="en">Basic Affiliation</desc>
        </state>
    </residence>
    <residence ref="#PL15767" key="2">
        <state>
            <desc xml:lang="zh-Hant">遷住地</desc>
            <desc xml:lang="en">Moved to</desc>
        </state>
    </residence>
    <residence ref="#PL15791" key="3">
        <state>
            <desc xml:lang="zh-Hant">前住地</desc>
            <desc xml:lang="en">Former Address</desc>
        </state>
    </residence>
    <note type="created" target="#TTS">
        <date when="2007-03-12"/>
    </note>
</person>