<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<person xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" ana="historical" xml:id="BIO12843">
    <idno type="TTS">7140</idno>
    <persName type="main">
        <persName xml:lang="zh-Hant">
            <surname>敬</surname>
            <forename>晤</forename>
            <addName type="choronym">平陽</addName>
        </persName>
        <persName xml:lang="zh-Latn-alalc97">
            <surname>Jing</surname>
            <forename>Wu</forename>
            <addName type="choronym">Pingyang</addName>
        </persName>
    </persName>
    <sex value="1">m</sex>
    <floruit>
        <date when="0830" datingMethod="#chinTrad" period="#D6">唐</date>
    </floruit>
    <note>Jing(5) Wu [12843] Wen(2) Yanbo [1953], WJ, 12.10a would have Wu as a great grandson of the Tang Zaixiang, Hui [12842]. The XTS genealogical tables are confusing and have gaps, which make this possible at the same time that it is also chronologically logical. This would make Wu a descendant of Fayan [12840] rather than Faming [12841] as might appear in the genealogical tables. Moreover, the XTS has Fayan as a son and Faying (not in dataset) as a younger brother of Xianjun [12838], whereas Zhou Jiayou has Fayan as a younger brother of Xianjun. Son is more logical chronologically. Therefore, I am making Fayan a son of Xianjun (generational name also makes more sense), Hui a fifth generation descendant of Fayan and Wu a great grandson of Hui. Hui is listed in Renming Da cidian as a Jiangzhou, Taiping person with comment on confusion with Pingyang. However, Pingyang can refer to the whole area or serve just as a choronym. Wen(2) Yanbo has the move of Wu's son to Fenzhou from Hedong county (modern Yongyi(b)-s). I am going to move Hui to Jiangzhou, but (as is common) keep the lineage descendants (i.e. a son remained in Yongji) in Hezhong until the move to Fenzhou.</note>
    <affiliation>
        <note>
            <listPerson>
                <personGrp role="kin"/>
                <listRelation type="kinship">
                    <relation active="#BIO12843" passive="#BIO12842" key="48" sortKey="-5" name="FFF">
                        <desc>
                            <desc xml:lang="en">FFF</desc>
                            <desc xml:lang="zh-Hant">曾祖</desc>
                        </desc>
                    </relation>
                    <relation active="#BIO12843" passive="#BIO12844" key="180" sortKey="5" name="S">
                        <desc>
                            <desc xml:lang="en">S Son</desc>
                            <desc xml:lang="zh-Hant">子</desc>
                        </desc>
                    </relation>
                </listRelation>
            </listPerson>
        </note>
    </affiliation>
    <socecStatus>
        <state type="status">
            <desc xml:lang="en">civil office</desc>
            <desc xml:lang="zh-Hant">[為官者：文]</desc>
        </state>
    </socecStatus>
    <residence ref="#PL15003" key="1">
        <state>
            <desc xml:lang="zh-Hant">籍貫(基本地址)</desc>
            <desc xml:lang="en">Basic Affiliation</desc>
        </state>
    </residence>
    <note type="created" target="#TTS">
        <date when="2007-03-12"/>
    </note>
</person>